#### ZIA



Vårlöksgatan 2C, 41706 GÖTEBORG

**u** 0046-72-121 71 74 🖨 0046-76-988 57 45

zia\_gt@yahoo.com

**DOB**: 1985-03-13

Portfolio: https://ziaongit.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://se.linkedin.com/in/zia-ullah

*GitHub:* https://github.com/ziaongit *Fiverr:* https://www.fiverr.com/ziacanic

## Summary:

I am a certified Front-End Developer, with extensive experience in Front-End Web Design/Development technologies. In Back-End Web Development NodeJS, ExpressJS, PHP, MongoDB, and PhpMySQL are my areas of work. Dedicated, responsible, team player, a hardworking and fast learner with a knack for problem-solving. Have worked both independently and in a team for agile development of company products.

### Skills

**Front-End Development**: HTML/HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3 & 4, Foundation, Materialize CSS, LESS/SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React JS, Grunt/Gulp, HTML5 Graphics (Canvas, SVG, Icon, Google Map), CMS (WordPress, Drupal, and Joomla)

*Graphics Design Skills*: Adobe Photoshop CS6, Typography Skills, Print Design, Layout /Conversion Optimization Skills, Color Theory

Back-End Development: PHP (Procedural and OOP), NodeJS, ExpressJS

Database: MySQL, MongoDB

SEO: On-Page SEO (Internal linking, Anchor text, Headlines, Titles and Meta tags, XML

Sitemap, Navigation, Comments, Content, Regularity, Length, Improving click through rates, Meta description research, Authorship, Schema mark-up, Images), Off-page SEO (link building, Social media, Keyword research, Google ad words,

Directories)

Other: Windows OS, Unix/Linux, Git, XML, Rest API, Scrum.

### **Projects**

- *Map Observer*: Icomera desktop application (Single page application)
  - My concern: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Less, Bootstrap, Working with rest API
- Lager books: Books library management system (www.lagerbooks.com)
  - Technologies: OOP PHP, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, CSS, Less, Bootstrap 3
- · Article Management System: Designed and Developed IT Articles Management website
  - Technologies: PHP, PhpMySQL, Adobe Photoshop, Dreamviewer
- · Car App: Car reaping management system
  - Technologies: OOP PHP, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap 3
- Portfolio: https://ziaongit.github.io/#portfolio
  - Portfolio section: Check my portfolio section for latest projects using above link

# Professional experience

*Period:* October 2016 – February 2017 *Company:* Icomera AB - Gothenburg, Sweden

**Position:** Front-end Developer

Responsibilities:

• Developing frontend GUI for in house applications

- Developing solutions that take advantage of available APIs and customer integrations
- Developing customer-specific portals
- Develop, enhance and implement tests for Icomera solutions and development work.

Technologies: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3 (Bootstrap, LESS/SASS), JavaScript, JQuery, PHP (Procedural OOP), and Web Services

Period: January 2010 – Present Freelance World Network Ltd Web Developer/Designer

Responsibilities:

Web Design/Development

Social media and Email marketing

SEO (On-Page, Off-Page, Keyword Research, Google Ad words)

**Technologies:** HTML/HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 3 & 4, Foundation, Materialize CSS, LESS/SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React JS, Grunt/Gulp, HTML5 Graphics (Canvas, SVG, Icon, Google Map), CMS (WordPress, Drupal, and Joomla), PHP (Procedural and OOP), NodelS, Express S and On-Page / Off-page SEO technologies.

*Period:* March 2009 – August 2010

Company: Sampotek Webzone Inc. - Peshawar, Pakistan

**Position:** Web Developer/Designer

Responsibilities:

Graphics Design

Frontend/Backend PHP, JavaScript, CSS scripting

· Implementing jQuery and Ajax solutions

CURL scripting for crawling data

## **Education and Training**

*Master (2011 – 2014):* Master in Computer and System Sciences

Institution: Stockholm University (Sweden)

Bachelor (2005 - 2009): Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

*Institution:* Gomal University (Pakistan)

*Front End (2017):* Front End Development Certification

Institution: Free Code Camp (Pakistan)

*COA (2009 – 2010):* Web Development and Design

Institution: IT Switchers (Pakistan)

*MCSE* (2009 – 2010): Microsoft Certified System Engineering

Institution: IT Switchers (Pakistan)

### Activities and interests

Watching movies, blogging, stacksoverflow, computer games, cricket and fitness.

### <u>Languages</u>